Remember how earlier we talked about the possibility of setting yourself a problem that
之前我们提到 我们设置的问题可能没有解
doesn't have a solution because there is no answer that satisfies all the constraints?
因为没有满足所有约束条件的答案
Well, that can happen in practice.
现实中可能会这样
When you're working with two or three dimensional problems
在处理二维或三维问题时
where you can graph the functions and observe what's going on,
我们可以画出函数图形并观察函数
it might be easier to see when the problem becomes infeasible.
更容易判断何时问题无解
However, in practice you're working in
但是在实践中
a high-dimensional space where it's hard to visualize what's going on.
我们处于高维空间 很难用图形的方式观察问题
In general learning what makes the problem infeasible comes with experience.
通常 判断问题是否无解需要经验积累
So, much of this might sound rather abstract,
所以这部分讨论的很多知识听起来很抽象
but we want to have a short discussion here to give you an intuition.
但是我们希望简单讨论一下 让你有大致的概念
One possible situation where this might arise,
出现无解的一种可能情形是
is if you fix the weight on a particular stock.
需要拟合特定股票的权重
For example, sometimes for some reason the compliance group at
例如 因为某些原因 公司的合规团队
your company may restrict trading company wide on a particular stock.
可能会在公司范围对特定股票的交易设定限制
So, there may be some stock that you can't
有些股票可能无法交易
trade or there may be a particular stock that's difficult to short,
或者某个股票难以做空
so again, you'd like to constrain the weight on that stock.
你需要对这个股票施加约束条件
However, if you put a hard constraint on the weight on that particular stock,
但是 如果对该股票的权重施加硬性约束条件
this might cause you to reach an infeasible solution in your optimization problem.
可能会导致优化问题无解
Let's just say first that it's often dangerous to put
首先 通常在优化问题中
equality constraints in an optimization problem
添加等式约束条件很危险
because the problem can get infeasible very easily.
因为问题很容易变得无解
Remember that inequality constraint is
等式约束条件
a much stronger condition than an inequality constraint.
是比不等式约束条件更严格的条件
It's the difference between requiring that they answer
例如 就好比要求解落在直线上
lie on a line or below a line, for example.
还是位于直线下方 二者差别很大的
Infeasibility is an issue with your constraints.
约束条件导致问题无解
One possible solution is to move
一种可能的解决办法是
one or more constraints to penalty terms in the objective function.
将一个或多个约束条件移到目标函数的惩罚项中
This changes the problem from placing a hard limit
这样就从对某个量设定严格限制
on some quantity to seeking to minimize that quantity,
变成了最小化这个量
but balanced against the other terms in the objective.
但是与目标函数中的其他项产生平衡
So, what are general rules of thumb or
那么在实践中避免这些情形的
guidelines for avoiding these situations in practice?
一般指南是什么呢？
In production you're inheriting a live portfolio.
在工作中 你会拿到一个实际的投资组合
Your job in optimization is to transition that portfolio to a new state using new data,
你的优化职责是使用新的数据和新的 Alpha 因子
new Alpha factors, and keeping in mind that
将该投资组合变成新的状态
market movements have caused the old weights to change slightly.
注意 市场变化已经导致原来的权重有所变化
The first thing to check is whether
首先需要检查
the starting portfolio produces an infeasible problem or not.
起始投资组合是否无解
In general start with fewer terms in the objective function.
通常 先向目标函数中添加更少的项
If that problem becomes infeasible,
如果问题变得无解
try to figure out which constraints are the ones causing the infeasibility,
试着判断哪些约束条件导致问题无解
see if you can change or override any of those constraints.
看看能否更改或替换任何约束条件
Finally, consider moving constraints to penalty terms in the objective function.
最后 考虑将约束条件移到目标函数的惩罚项中